He works in mysterious ways.
Wake Up Dead Man: A Knives Out Mystery is a thriller,
mystery, comedy film directed by Rian Johnson.
When young priest Jud Duplenticy is sent to assist charismatic firebrand
Monsignor Jefferson Wicks, it’s clear that all is not well in the pews.
After a sudden and seemingly impossible murder rocks the town, the lack of an obvious suspect prompts local police chief
Geraldine Scott to join forces with renowned detective Benoit Blanc to unravel a mystery that defies all logic.
Benoit Blanc, played by Daniel Craig.
Fr. Jud Duplenticy, played by Josh O'Connor.
Martha Delacroix, played by Glenn Close.
Mons. Jefferson Wicks, played by Josh Brolin.
Chief Geraldine Scott, played by Mila Kunis.
Dr. Nat Sharp, played by Jeremy Renner.
Wake Up Dead Man (marketed as Wake Up Dead Man: A Knives Out Mystery) is a
2025 American mystery film written and directed by Rian Johnson.
It is the third film in the Knives Out series.
The film stars Daniel Craig, who reprises his role
as master detective Benoit Blanc.
In the film, Blanc investigates the death of a divisive Catholic
priest against the backdrop of a missing inheritance.
The ensemble cast also includes Josh O'Connor, Glenn Close, Josh Brolin, Mila Kunis, Jeremy Renner,
Kerry Washington, Andrew Scott, Cailee Spaeny, Daryl McCormack, and Thomas Haden Church.
The film had its world premiere at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 6, 2025, and was
released in select theaters on November 26, 2025, before streaming on Netflix on December 12, 2025.
Like its predecessors, it received generally positive reviews, with most praise
for the performances, in particular those of Craig and O'Connor.
The film explores themes of detective, investigation, sequel, murder, whodunit.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and mind_bending.